Connecticut Nurses' Association Records
© 2005 University of Connecticut
- Series I: Records, 1933-1986
  - 1985
    - Working Effectively with the Media - New Haven Hospital (Box 11:, Folder 342)
  - 1986
    - Application of Sales Tax Exemption (Box 11:, Folder 343)
    - Board of Directors (Box 11:, Folder 344)
    - Bylaws (Box 11:, Folder 345)
    - Chairpersons Meeting (Box 11:, Folder 346)
    - CE Council (Box 11:, Folder 347)
    - CE Provider Unit (Box 11:, Folder 348)
    - CEARP Committee (Box 11:, Folder 349)
    - CCONO (Box 11:, Folder 350)
    - CNPAC (Box 11:, Folder 351)
    - Correspondence (Box 11:, Folder 352)
    - Diamond Jubilarian (Box 11:, Folder 353)
    - Diamond Jubilarian - Awards (Box 11:, Folder 354)
    - Eastern Seaboard Regional Executive Conference (ESREC) (Box 11:, Folder 355)
    - Economic and General Welfare Task Force (Box 11:, Folder 356)
    - Ethics Committee (Box 11:, Folder 357)
    - Executive Board of Directors (Box 11:, Folder 358)
    - Finance Committee (Box 11:, Folder 359)
    - Gerontology Division (Box 11:, Folder 360)
    - Government Relation Committee (Box 11:, Folder 361)
    - Grants (Box 11:, Folder 362)
    - Guidelines for Nurses (Box 11:, Folder 363)
    - House of Delegates (Box 11:, Folder 364)
    - Membership ANA Correspondence (Box 11:, Folder 365)
    - Membership Special Project (1985?) (Box 11:, Folder 366)
    - Nominating Committee (Box 11:, Folder 367)
    - Nursing Diagnosis (Box 11:, Folder 368)
    - Nursing Education Cabinet (Box 11:, Folder 369)
    - Nursing Practice Cabinet (Box 11:, Folder 370)
    - Nursing Research (Box 11:, Folder 371)
    - Department of the Navy (Box 11:, Folder 372)
    - Nursing Shortage (Box 11:, Folder 373)
    - Parent / Child Nursing Council (Box 11:, Folder 374)
    - Peer Assistance Network (Box 11:, Folder 375)
    - Professional and Public Relation Council (Box 11:, Folder 376)
    - Psych. Mental Health Division (Box 11:, Folder 377)
    - Resolutions (Box 11:, Folder 378)
    - Strategic Planning (Box 11:, Folder 379)
    - Task Force on Redistricting Resolution (Box 11:, Folder 380)
- Series II: Historical Material, 1893-1988
  - Accomplishments by CAN, 1904-1957 (Box 12:, Folder 381)
  - Fact Sheet, 1901-1973 (Box 12:, Folder 382)
  - Articles of Association of The Graduate Nurses' Association of Connecticut, 1904 (Box 12:, Folder 383)
  - Receipt for Organization Fee of The Graduate Nurses Association of Connecticut, 1904 (Box 12:, Folder 384)
  - Receipt for Certificate of Articles of Association of Graduate Nurses' Association of Connecticut, 1904 (Box 12:, Folder 385)
  - Receipt of Town Clerk's Office for Articles of Association of the Graduate Nurses Association of Connecticut, 1904 (Box 12:, Folder 386)
  - Articles of Incorporation and Bylaws, 1922 (Box 12:, Folder 387)
  - Constitution and Bylaws National Organization for Public Health, 1927 (Box 12:, Folder 388)
  - Articles of Association and Bylaws of the Graduate Nurses' Association, 1927 (Box 12:, Folder 389)
  - Historical Sketch of ANA, 1929 (Box 12:, Folder 390)
  - Membership Cards (Lucy Clinch), 1930-1946, 1948-1968 (Box 12:, Folder 391)
  - Amendment to Articles of Association of the Graduate Nurses' Association of Connecticut, 1932 (Box 12:, Folder 392)
  - Receipt for Certificate of Amendment of Articles of Association of Graduate Nurses' Association, 1932 (Box 12:, Folder 393)
  - Amendment to Articles of Association of the Graduate Nurses' Association of Connecticut, 1932 (Box 12:, Folder 394)
  - The Association of Collegiate Schools of Nursing, 1936 (Box 12:, Folder 395)
  - Nursing News CNA, 1944 (Box 12:, Folder 396)
  - Receipt for Certificate of Amendment to Articles of Association of the Connecticut State Nurses' Association, 1948 (Box 12:, Folder 397)
  - Town Clerk's Office Recording Receipt of Amendment of Articles of Association of the Connecticut State Nurses' Association, 1949 (Box 12:, Folder 398)
  - Amendment to Articles of Association of the Connecticut State Nurses' Association, 1949 (Box 12:, Folder 399)
  - Five Decades Historical Sketch of Connecticut State Nurses' Association, 1954 (Box 12:, Folder 400)
  - Position Form of Schedule Fidelity Bond- Great American Indemnity Company, New York, 1954 (Box 12:, Folder 401)
  - Nursing News CNA, 1955 (Box 12:, Folder 402)
  - Amendment to Articles of Association of the Connecticut State Nurses' Association, 1958 (Box 12:, Folder 403)
  - Nursing News CNA Sixth Decade Commemorative Issue, 1964 (Box 12:, Folder 404)
  - “It All Began in New Haven” New Haven Register Article, 1973 (Box 12:, Folder 405)
  - “Memorabilia From Six Nurses, New to Hall of Fame on Display in Special Exhibition at Convention” ANA Article Convention News, 1982 (Box 12:, Folder 406)
  - Nursing Shortage Pay Raise Article, 1988 (Box 12:, Folder 407)
  - Pictures: Annie Warburton Goodrich (Box 12:, Folder 408)
    - Linda Richards
    - Effie Taylor
    - Agnes Ohlson
    - Virginia Henderson
  - “Three Score Years and Ten” National League for Nursing, 1893-1963 (Box 13:, Folder 409)
  - The American Journal of Nursing and its Company, 1900-1975 (Box 13:, Folder 410)
  - The Story of The American Journal of Nursing, 1940 (Box 13:, Folder 411)
  - “Tomorrows and Yesterdays, as Told on the Fiftieth Anniversary of the Association's Founding.” ANA, 1946 (Box 13:, Folder 412)
  - “Confessions of a Committee Woman”, 1949 (Box 13:, Folder 413)
  - Annie Warburton Goodrich- Dean of the School of Nursing at Yale University, 1955 (Box 13:, Folder 414)
  - ANA CT State Nurses' Association Agreement for Total Service, June 23, 1961 (Box 13:, Folder 415)
  - Firestone Realty Service Letter for 84 West Avon Road, May 24, 1968 (Box 13:, Folder 416)
  - Connecticut Nurses' Associations' Constitution and Bylaws Revision, 1971 (Box 13:, Folder 417)
  - First 50 Years and First 75 Years- ANA, 1971 (Box 13:, Folder 418)
  - “Acute Psychiatric Services for Conference on Emergency Nursing” D. Pet, MD, 1972 (Box 13:, Folder 419)
  - Definition of a Nurse, 1972 (Box 13:, Folder 420)
  - “Nurse Practice Act”, Marie Turbie Speech, 1972 (Box 13:, Folder 421)
  - Poulos, Barry V Kuzmak/ Letter for Lease between Old Farms Realty November 9, 1972 (Box 13:, Folder 422)
  - “Recent Legal Developments Concerning the Expanding Nursing Role”, 1972 (Box 13:, Folder 423)
  - Historic Letters, 1973-1996 (Box 13:, Folder 424)
  - Nurse practice Act Historical Materials, 1975 (Box 13:, Folder 425)
  - Connecticut Nurses Association Bicentennial Calendar, 1976-1977 (Box 13:, Folder 426)
  - “Emerging and Developing Family” Keynote Address V. Keane May, 1976 (Box 13:, Folder 427)
  - ANA Nursing Hall of Fame, 1981-1982 (Box 13:, Folder 428)
  - “Helping Nurses Bargain for More than They Got” Mary Lou Millar, 1982 (Box 13:, Folder 429)
  - “From Out of Antiquity Personal Reflections”, 1983 (Box 13:, Folder 430)
  - Reflections- ANA Convention Beverly O'Connor, 1984 (Box 13:, Folder 431)
  - “Clarion Call” - Allison Bailey (Box 13:, Folder 432)
  - Economic Security Program Speeches (Box 13:, Folder 433)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 13:, Folder 434)
  - Nurse Practice Act
    - Nurse Practice Act Hearings Sept. 19, 1974, Danbury Sept. 24, 1974, Norwich (Box 14:, Folder 435)
    - Nurse Practice Act Hearings Oct. 3, 1974, Hartford (Box 14:, Folder 436)
    - Nurse Practice Act Hearings Oct. 8, 1974, Storrs (Box 14:, Folder 437)
    - Nurse Practice Act Hearings Oct. 17, 1974, Bridgeport (Box 14:, Folder 438)
    - Nurse Practice Act Hearings Oct. 10, 1974, New Haven (Box 14:, Folder 439)
    - Nurse Practice Act -Connecticut (Box 14:, Folder 440)
    - Nurse Practice Act -Minutes, 1971-1975 (Box 14:, Folder 441)
    - Legal Control- Nursing Practice Acts, 1959 (Box 14:, Folder 442)
    - Marie Turbie Reports, 1972 (Box 14:, Folder 443)
    - Legislation Survey, 1973 (Box 14:, Folder 444)
    - CNA Ad Hoc Committee NPA, 1974 (Box 14:, Folder 445)
    - Nursing Diagnosis and SB 1485, 1975 (Box 14:, Folder 446)
    - Nurse Practice Act Nursing News Article and Governor's Proposed Amendment, 1976 (Box 14:, Folder 447)
    - General Statutes of CT Chapter 378-Nursing, 1977 (Box 14:, Folder 448)
    - Nurse Practice Act to be amended, 1979 (Box 14:, Folder 449)
    - Professional Association and State Legislation and Nurse Practice Act excerpts from ten states, 1981 (Box 14:, Folder 450)
    - Nurse Practice Act from several states, 1982 (Box 14:, Folder 451)
    - State Board of Examiners-Nurse Practice Act Louisiana lawsuit article and Maine Amendment article, 1983 (Box 14:, Folder 452)
    - State Board of Examiners reports of various states, 1984 (Box 14:, Folder 453)
    - Statements - Diagnosis (Box 14:, Folder 454)
    - Questionnaire, 1972 (Box 14:, Folder 455)
  - Entry Into Practice
    - Guide for Recording/Reporting Group Discussion (Box 14:, Folder 456)
    - Leaders Sites OK'd District I (Box 14:, Folder 457)
    - Leaders Sites OK'd District III (Box 14:, Folder 458)
    - Leaders Sites OK'd District IV (Box 14:, Folder 459)
    - Leaders Sites OK'd District V (Box 14:, Folder 460)
    - Leaders and Training (Box 14:, Folder 461)
    - Leaders Reports (Box 14:, Folder 462)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Center for Nursing Innovations (Box 14:, Folder 463)
    - Connecticut League for Nursing, 1972 (Box 14:, Folder 464)
    - Connecticut Hospital Association, 1971-1973 (Box 14:, Folder 465)
    - Connecticut Peer Review Organization (Box 14:, Folder 466)
    - Equal Rights Amendment (Box 14:, Folder 467)
    - Licensed Practical Nurse (Box 14:, Folder 468)
    - Nurse Expert Witness Task Force (Box 14:, Folder 469)
    - Nursing Shortage - Janet McMahon (Box 14:, Folder 470)
    - The Patient's Right to Know - Sept. 1975 Convention (Box 14:, Folder 471)
    - The Role of the Family Nurse Practitioner (Box 14:, Folder 472)
- Series III: Connecticut Nursing News, 1923-1987
  - Connecticut State Nurses Association Bulletin- Volume 37, 1923-1929 (Box 14:, Folder 473)
  - CSNA Nursing News
    - Volume 38, 1930-1937 (Box 14:, Folder 474)
    - No Volume Number, 1921-1929 (Box 15:, Folder 475)
    - Volume 3, 1938 January - 1946 February (Box 15:, Folder 476)
    - Volume 4, 1946 May - 1949 December (Box 15:, Folder 477)
    - Volume 23-27, 1950-1954 (Box 15:, Folder 478)
    - Volume 28-29, 1955-1956 (Box 15:, Folder 479)
    - Volume 30, 1957; (2 copies) (Box 15:, Folder 480)
    - Volume 31-32, 1958-1959 (Box 15:, Folder 481)
    - Volume 34-35, 1960-1961 (Box 15:, Folder 482)
    - Volume 36-37, 1962-1963 (Box 15:, Folder 483)
    - Volume 38-39, 1964-1965 (Box 15:, Folder 484)
    - Volume 40-41, 1966-1967 (Box 16:, Folder 485)
    - Volume 42-43, 1968-1969 (Box 16:, Folder 486)
    - Volume 44-46, 1970-1972 (Box 16:, Folder 487)
  - Connecticut Nursing News
    - Microfilm, 1976 September - 1977 August (Box 16:, Folder 488)
    - Microfilm, 1977 September - 1978 August (Box 16:, Folder 489)
    - Microfilm, 1978 September - 1979 August (Box 16:, Folder 490)
    - Monthly- missing July and August, 1970 (Box 16:, Folder 491)
    - January, June, September- December, 1971 (Box 16:, Folder 492)
    - Monthly- missing July, August, October, and November, 1972 (Box 16:, Folder 493)
    - Monthly- missing January, June, July, and August, 1973 (Box 16:, Folder 494)
    - 1974 (Box 16:, Folder 495)
    - 1975 (Box 16:, Folder 496)
    - Monthly- missing February, March, and July, 1977 (Box 16:, Folder 497)
    - September and December, 1978 (Box 16:, Folder 498)
    - February, April, May, November, and December, 1979 (Box 16:, Folder 499)
    - Monthly- missing January, May, July, and August, 1980 (Box 16:, Folder 500)
    - Monthly- missing December, 1981 (Box 16:, Folder 501)
    - Monthly- missing November, 1982 (Box 16:, Folder 502)
    - 1983 (Box 16:, Folder 503)
    - 1984 (Box 16:, Folder 504)
    - 1985 (Box 16:, Folder 505)
    - 1986 (Box 16:, Folder 506)
    - 1987 (Box 16:, Folder 507)